Ashley Wright

918 Dancing Waters • Forney, TX 75126 • (214) 679-8064 • ashleyaggie@aol.com

https://linkedin.com/in/ashley-wright-580471105/ • https://github.com/ashleyaggie • https://ashleyaggie.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Software engineer with a background in English and creative arts from Texas A&M. Certificate in Full Stack Development from SMU with skills in HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript. Creative problem-solver that is always interested in learning more to develop user-friendly designs. Strengths include creativity, executing client vision, and detail-oriented solutions.

Earned employee of the year at a previous position, grade average in the course is an A+, and developed a web application for an assignment that can save user input in local storage and populate on page load. Dedicated and detail-oriented with a history of coordinating with other departments within companies worked for in the past. Very meticulous and interested in fulfilling the design in the cleanest and clearest ways possible.

PROJECTS

Marvel Character Directory

Developed a website with a group that pulls information from API's to display based on what Marvel character the user chooses. Used mainly HTML and JavaScript with Materialize CSS elements.

https://github.com/leviathan902/Marvel-Character-Movie-Selector

Weather Dashboard

Created a website that shows the current weather in whatever city the user searches and provides the forecast for the next 5 days. Mostly JavaScript with some HTML and CSS. https://github.com/ashleyaggie/WeatherDashboard

Code Quiz

An application that uses JavaScript and HTML to enact a quiz over basic coding concepts. The JavaScript edits the HTML to display the questions. Coded from HTML and JavaScript with some minor CSS. https://github.com/ashleyaggie/CodeQuiz

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Results Staffing, Dallas, TX

November 2018 – January 2021

Administration Payroll Specialist

The Reynolds & Reynolds Co., College Station, TX

• Hardware Installation Coordinator

January 2016 - July 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Adobe Photoshop, Microsoft Office, and TempsPlus. Typing speed ~100 wpm.

Skilled in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript with experience using Bootstrap and Materialize.

EDUCATION

SMU Coding Boot Camp, Dallas, TX

January 2021 – Current

Certification in Full Stack Web Development

Texas A&M University, College Station, TX

December 2015

Bachelor of Arts of English - Creative Writing Track

Minor in Art - New Media Track

Study Abroad: Kukulcan Language Center, Cuernavaca, MX

July – August 2014

Four week study abroad learning about Mexican culture and the language. Stayed with a host family and went on trips to other cities in Mexico to explore the country more.

HONORS